

guzmán**López**

Marine Biologist and IT Analyst student

about

30 years Male, Uruguayan Montevideo, Uruguay

contact

languages

Spanish Native proficiency English Elementary proficiency

programming

R Language (6 Years)JavaScript, HTML5 &CSS (3 Years)

Additional knowledge on SQL ASP.Net with C#

08

Linux

interests

professional: Data Analytics, Big Data, Programming, Research, Databases, Spatial analysis, Geographic Information Systems, Hydroacoustics, Seabed habitat mapping, Echosounders, Sonars, Marine ecology, Fisheries, Fish behavior, Marine Traffic analysis **personal:** Friends, Tango dancing (Teaching & Dancing), Hiking, Ocean, Wildlife, Books.

education

2015-Now IT Analyst

ORT University - Faculty of Engineering, Montevideo

Courses until now:

Databases II (SQL syntax, queries, triggers) - Currently studying

Programming III (ASP.Net with C#) – Currently studying

Databases I (SQL syntax, queries, ERM) - 82/100 (partially approved, last

exam)

Programming II (ASP.Net with C#) – 88/100 (partially approved, last exam) Usability and Accessibility workshop (CSS) – 96/100 (totally approved)

Programming I (JS, HTML) – 100/100 (totally approved) Computing Introduction – 86/100 (totally approved)

2004-2011 **Biology sciences graduate** University of the Republic – Faculty of Sciences, Montevideo

Specialization in Oceanography

Global mark: 9.44 1 to 12 (max)

Courses: 23 approved / 23 total

Exams: 26 approved / 24 total (+2 exonerated)

2003 **Bachelor Degree** Pre-University Institute Juan XXIII, Montevideo

Specialization in Agronomy

Mark: 9 1 to 12 (max)

1998-2002 High School Student

Pallotti High School, Montevideo

Specialization in Biology

Marks: 12 (1998) - 12 (1999) - 11 (2000) - 12 (2001) - 11 (2002) 1 to 12 (max)

experience

2014-Now National Direction of Aquatic Resources (DINARA)

Montevideo, Uruguay

Hydroacoustic consultant

Acquisition, processing, visualization and analysis of scientific echosounder and sonar data.

2013 **Project: FREPLATA II (PNUD - GEF)**

Montevideo, Uruguay

Oceanographic data management assistant

Organization, systematization and analysis of historical and new generated data relating to meteorological and oceanographic variables.

2010-2012 **Project: Fisheries Management in Uruguay (DINARA - FAO)** Montevideo, Uruguay **Hydroacoustic consultant specialist**

Acquisition, processing, visualization and analysis of scientific echosounder and sonar data.

2009 Subprojects: Whitemouth croaker and Argentine hake (FAO - Ricaldoni Foundation)

Montevideo, Uruguay

Hydroacoustic technical support

Acquisition, processing, visualization and analysis of scientific echosounder data from Argentine hake and Whitemouth croaker fish abundance assessment surveys abroad research vessel "Aldebarán".

2008 National Direction of Aquatic Resources (DINARA)

Montevideo, Uruguay

Hydroacoustic collaborator.

Help acquiring, processing and visualizing acoustic data from the research survey: "Assessment of the Hawkfish by means of hydroacoustic methods and classic swap area in the Uruguayan Exclusive Economic Zone (EEZ)", abroad the research vessel "Aldebarán".

research

2007-Now Activities:

+25 research reports

+15 research surveys abroad different vessels

13 complementary courses

7 communication instances (oral presentations and posters)

4 different teaching instances

3 peer-reviewed co-author articles

2 student research projects

complementary courses

most important

2014	Introduction to databases analysis using R Approved: without mark	University of the Republic - Course
2014	Linux network administration Mark: 100/100	Linux Center - Course
2011	Introduction to R language programming Approved: without mark	University of the Republic - Course
2009	Effective publication of scientific information Approved: without mark	UNESCO - Course

publications

most important